## **Rustam Khuseinov**

# Frontend Software Engineer

▼ rustamjon.khuseinov@gmail.com rustamkhuseinov.com in linkedin.com/in/rustamkhuseinov

I am a software engineer specializing in frontend development. My passion is creating web applications that combine functionality and visual inspiration. Outside of work, my interests extend to the world of video games, which inspires my creativity, and football, where I find a source of team spirit and passion. My goal is to apply my skills and passions to create unique and outstanding web applications.

## **Experience**

## Feb 2022 - Present

#### Frontend developer at Profisites (Remote) *⊘*

- Dushanbe, Tajikistan
  Actively used TypeScript and React to optimize the performance and stability of web applications.
  - Conducted a successful project migration process from using vanilla HTML, CSS and JavaScript to more modern technologies, including TypeScript, React and Styled Components.
  - Supported a set of components for the UI-Kit, which helped standardize the design and speed up development.
  - Introduced updated technologies and design solutions for websites, which simplified development and reduced the time spent on selecting products and placing orders by more than 50%.

### Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

#### Kazan, Russia

#### Internship at Aston 🔗

- Participation in the Online JS Core intensive, which included theoretical classes, practice and homework, which gave me a solid foundation in JavaScript, HTML/CSS and working with Git.
- Continuation of the internship as part of the Online React-intensive, with an emphasis on developing web applications in React and TypeScript, as well as participation in group projects.
- Completion of an internship at the Laboratory, where, under the guidance of experienced specialists, I developed not only technical skills, but also soft skills, preparing for work on commercial projects.

#### Jan 2021 - Oct 2021

#### Kazan, Russia

#### Self-education

rustamkhuseinov.com &

• In-depth study of JavaScript/TypeScript/React and related technologies using them in your own projects.

#### **Technical Skill**

#### Front End Development

TypeScript, JavaScript(ES6+), React, Redux (Thunk,Toolkit), HTML, CSS, SCSS/Sass, Webpack, Vite, Parcel, Styled Components, Framer Motion

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, GitHub, Figma, Photoshop, Postman, Jest, Jira, Vercel, Netlify, Trello.

#### **Education**

2018 - 2023 Kazan National Research Technological University *⊘* 

Kazan, Russia Bachelor's Degree in Tourism

2016 − 2018 Kazan State University Ø

Kazan, Russia Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science